在平板的网格图中，当一个列表被选择后，
In the tablet wireframes, when a list item is selected
会显示一个蓝色的激活框的背景。通过设置背景的状态
it shows this blue activated state background. This can be done
列表可以被设置成为
by setting the background of the list item to be
可绘型。我们看看文档是怎么在以下说明
a state drawable. We can look at the documentation for the
StateListDrawable 的。
StateListDrawable, which is linked below.
本质上，一个StateListDrawable 可以允许你
Essentially a StateListDrawable allows you
基于不同的界面特别的选出不同的可绘型模板。
to specify different drawables based on the state of the view.
我们提供了StateListDrawable的一些代码。把这些代码
We provide you the code for the StateListDrawable. Drop it in
放进res目录下的一个drawable 文件夹里。当设置一个
by creating a drawable folder under the res directory. When set
选项列表的背景时，这个touch selector将会显示成
on the background of a list item, the touch selector will
默认的透明色。这跟我们可以看到的一样，这个活动的背景
appear transparent by default. As seen here we just see the background
显示出来。当这个界面被按下之后我们可以看到一个
of the activity come through. When the view is pressed then
灰色的背景。当状态被激活之后，我们看到一个
we see a grey background. Then when the state is activated we
蓝色的背景。这说明被选的选项进入了
see a blue background. This indicates that it's the selected item
支付模式。在列表布局界面，我们要设置背景为
into pay mode. In the list item layout, we set the background
可绘型的touch selector。同样今天我们也需要
to be this drawable touch selector. We also did the same
这样的设置。在touch selector文件里， 可以看到
for the today layout. In the touch selector file, we also see
颜色控制的选项。这个安卓颜色标注是用来
that we have some colors defined here. That Android color notation
给一个框架设置颜色的。颜色其实是在colors.xml文件里。
is for a framework defined color. Our colors are in the colors.xml
目录是在values文件夹下。这给开发者提供了一些帮助，当你需要
file. This is located under the values folder. This us useful
多次参考一些颜色的时候。再来一个小线索，
if you need to reference colors multiple times in your app. As
当需要做一个列表来显示它的状态时，
a hint, to make a list item show its activated state,
你可以在XML属性表里找到list view 的属性。
you can look at the documentation for the XML attribute choice mode
你一旦找到对的属性，就可以
for the list view. Once you find the right attribute, you'll realize
看到单窗的属性和双窗属性有什么不同。
that you want different behavior for one pane versus two pane mode.
同时你也可以在Java代码里修改这些设置，
While you could change the behavior programmatically in the Java
我的建议是希望你能够完全从xml里面修改
code, we'd like you to do it purely via the resource
这些风格。 阅读下面的文档你可以
XML files using a style. Read this doc to learn
学到如何去定义XML里的属性，同时你也
about how styles can be defined in XML and use what
可以学到如何对不同屏幕大小的设备进行设置。
you learned earlier about defining alternative resources for different sized
普遍上来讲，设计风格就是你把所有关于界面的属性放在
devices. In general, styles are a way that you can group
一起。举个例子啊， 这些文字属性会来替换
together attributes for a view. For example, these text attributes
CodeFont的风格。CodeFont的风格其实是在
are replaced by this style CodeFont. The CodeFont styles is defined
styles.xml 文件里的，之前讲过，在values 文件夹。
in the styles.xml file, located in the values folder.
你可以通过设置父类的风格来定义
You can also have styles inherent other styles by specifying
子类的风格。这里还有一些其他的例子，你可以用来
the parent. There are a couple other examples that you
参考。好的，这就是你最后应用
can check out on this page. This is what the
看上去的样子了。有两个
app should look like when you're done. The two
窗口来显示被选择过的状态。在
pane mode shows the pressed and activated state. On the
网页窗口中，我们只能看到按下的状态，因为
web pane mode, we see just the press state, because
按下选项之后会显示细节在屏幕上。
tapping on an item brings you to the details screen.